{
  "year3Ques": [
      {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "The pascaline was invented by __________.",
        "options": ["Blaise Pascal", "John Napier", "William Oughtred"],
        "answer": "Blaise Pascal"
      },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "Who is the father of computer?",
        "options": ["Augusta Byron", "Blaise Pascal", "Charles Babbage"],
        "answer": "Charles Babbage"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "How old was Blaise Pascal when he invented the pascaline?",
        "options": ["20 years old", "21 years old", "19 years old"],
        "answer": "19 years old"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "The first female programmer is __________.",
        "options": ["Ngozi Ifeanyi", "Ada Augusta Byron", "Adichie Chimamanda"],
        "answer": "Ada Augusta Byron"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "The two machines invented by Charles Babbage were __________.",
        "options": ["Input and output device", "Analytical and difference engine", "Laptop and desktop"],
        "answer": "Analytical and difference engine"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Charles Babbage is from which country?",
        "options": ["Jamaica", "Australia", "England"],
        "answer": "England"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "What type of computer has the qualities of both an analogue and digital computer?",
        "options": ["Hybrid", "Analogue", "Digital"],
        "answer": "Hybrid"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "__________ are very fast computers that use binary (0 and 1) to display information.",
        "options": ["Hybrid", "Analogue", "Digital"],
        "answer": "Digital"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "__________ are computers that are slow to solve problems.",
        "options": ["Hybrid", "Analogue", "Digital"],
        "answer": "Analogue"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "A counting device using columns of beads that can move up and down is called __________.",
        "options": ["Hybrid", "Abacus", "Digital"],
        "answer": "Abacus"
      },
      {
        "id": 11,
        "question": "One of the following is not an example of an early counting device.",
        "options": ["Calculator", "Stones", "Pebbles"],
        "answer": "Calculator"
      },
      {
        "id": 12,
        "question": "__________ are devices used in ancient times to carry out arithmetic operations such as addition, subtraction, multiplication, and division.",
        "options": ["Mechanical devices", "Early counting devices", "Digital computers"],
        "answer": "Early counting devices"
      },
      {
        "id": 13,
        "question": "__________ is an electronic machine that performs different operations.",
        "options": ["Machine gun", "Television", "Computer"],
        "answer": "Computer"
      },
      {
        "id": 14,
        "question": "Computer is used for performing __________ operations.",
        "options": ["Walking", "Addition", "Cooking"],
        "answer": "Addition"
      },
      {
        "id": 15,
        "question": "__________ is an early counting device.",
        "options": ["Finger", "Calculator", "Computer"],
        "answer": "Finger"
      },
      {
        "id": 16,
        "question": "These are body counting devices.",
        "options": ["Stone, rock", "Stomach and stick", "Finger, toes"],
        "answer": "Finger, toes"
      },
      {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "Computer can be used everywhere except __________.",
        "options": ["Bank", "Toilet", "School"],
        "answer": "Toilet"
      },
      {
        "id": 18,
        "question": "__________ is used to print out our work.",
        "options": ["Monitor", "CPU", "Printer"],
        "answer": "Printer"
      },
      {
        "id": 19,
        "question": "The monitor is like a __________.",
        "options": ["Television", "Radio", "Nylon"],
        "answer": "Television"
      },
      {
        "id": 20,
        "question": "The mouse controls the __________ on the screen.",
        "options": ["Keyboard", "Cursor", "CPU"],
        "answer": "Cursor"
      }
    ]
  }
  